<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>essay on R.N. Shaw</title>
    <link>https://rnshaw.com/tags/essay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in essay on R.N. Shaw</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:02:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnshaw.com/tags/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Polite Children Don&#39;t Exist</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/polite-children-dont-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:02:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/polite-children-dont-exist/</guid>
      <description>I am incapable of returning items to a store. This problem is not entirely based on forgetfulness, though that does play a part, but is due to a phobia that I developed somewhere along the way. The idea of walking up to a counter and stating that I would like to return something sends shivers up my spine. If I attempt said act, I will surely be paralyzed by utter panic before I make it to the counter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hope Deferred</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/hope-deferred/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/hope-deferred/</guid>
      <description>Hope deferred makes the heart sick, but a desire fulfilled is a tree of life. Proverbs 13:12 ESV
 To love is to open the heart, to stretch out with trust and reach across the abyss of the unknown to another. When that love is not returned, the heart is overwhelmed with sickness. Thus it is that we turn to various remedies. We lower our expectations; we build up our resolve; we numb our pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkened Thoughts -or- Thoughts In Season</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/darkened-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/darkened-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>If it&amp;rsquo;s loneliness, it must be self-sustained. Some ever-long grasping which perpetuates the void.
Only in the Post-Modern can the theologian&amp;rsquo;s thoughts be judged by their sexiness.
It&amp;rsquo;s this slow moving boat, going nowhere.
This the nagging question, from what can we help someone else? Out of which storehouse and to which?
In a desert, surrounded only by threats and conquests. This, the atomic life.
Is it pleasure, tyrant over the soul, or a far deeper misfortune?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demands for Value</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/demands-for-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/demands-for-value/</guid>
      <description>Sometime last year, as darkness was creeping, I was asking &amp;lsquo;what for.&amp;rsquo; Unresolved, I drove to work. Night shift.
I turned to the East, my normal path, marking a course through veiled country fields, and turned to the driver&amp;rsquo;s side window. Painted across the black were the Northern Lights in full glory. I felt an Aurora virgin.
The lights struck me as an immediate though ambiguous answer: beauty. But more, a demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Hunt Transcendence</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/how-to-hunt-transcendence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/how-to-hunt-transcendence/</guid>
      <description>Identifying root emotions is tricky business. The quiet ones often do it well&amp;ndash;us watchers. We sit in café corners and look at the eyes floating about, disjointed from their bodies&amp;ndash;out of sync. The cues are subtle at first, but soon the art is mastered. We capture souls as they walk past.
I am a connoisseur of beautiful souls, and a surgeon. I snatch up the rare specimens and breathe them deep inside, pulling the layers off piece by piece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of the Nation</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/the-state-of-the-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/the-state-of-the-nation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Do you believe in God, Mr. Le Chiffre.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I believe in a reasonable rate of return.&amp;rdquo;
Casino Royale
 America may die a quick and brutish disintegration, but a reasonable citizen will not assume such gloomy forecasts in his budget. He will, instead, discuss the possibility of a reasonable rate of recovery and our future viability in the world market, and these choices of topics are rightly so. This massive organism whom we loosely call the American Economy is &amp;lsquo;too big to fail,&amp;rsquo; or more precisely, too big to perceive what a failure would look like or what exactly would be the implications of such a collapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coroner I Met at the Bar</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/coroner-i-met-at-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/coroner-i-met-at-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>When they banned smoking from bars here in . . . well, everywhere, the coroner marked the time and date for the spiritual meaning of the beloved saloon. The bar no longer makes sense, and I sit here and fondle the thought that this simple, pointed break is crackling now through the structure, the soft release of a delicate tension, and this thread skeleton sags under the breath of the still air, that artful balance of human nature which is the bar is now crumbling into a dull, dried splatter of blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unkempt</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/unkempt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/unkempt/</guid>
      <description>Around the perimeter of my property is an entire town of short grass, uncluttered yards and clean lines. Growing up we heard two equally persuasive refrains: &amp;ldquo;you are special&amp;rdquo; in terms of the positive and the future or &amp;ldquo;everyone goes through that&amp;rdquo; when it came to every real life event, so when I perceive that my life, at least on the surface, is uniquely in shambles&amp;ndash;the only crumbling brick in the pyramid&amp;ndash;my conscience applauds me on both ends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
