<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on R.N. Shaw</title>
    <link>https://rnshaw.com/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on R.N. Shaw</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnshaw.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Tears Nearby</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/the-tears-nearby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/the-tears-nearby/</guid>
      <description>These days, these precious days which I can hardly touch, my tears are always only ever a loosened breath away. I hate them, I miss them, I beckon them, and I retreat.
The days before I drove to the hospital, my mind was on the character of greatness. Across the hospital bed in the PICU, I watched my mother and her sad eyes reassure, caress, hold steady. Greatness is a calm and swelling ocean in a tender shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demands for Value</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/demands-for-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/demands-for-value/</guid>
      <description>Sometime last year, as darkness was creeping, I was asking &amp;lsquo;what for.&amp;rsquo; Unresolved, I drove to work. Night shift.
I turned to the East, my normal path, marking a course through veiled country fields, and turned to the driver&amp;rsquo;s side window. Painted across the black were the Northern Lights in full glory. I felt an Aurora virgin.
The lights struck me as an immediate though ambiguous answer: beauty. But more, a demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Hunt Transcendence</title>
      <link>https://rnshaw.com/essays/how-to-hunt-transcendence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnshaw.com/essays/how-to-hunt-transcendence/</guid>
      <description>Identifying root emotions is tricky business. The quiet ones often do it well&amp;ndash;us watchers. We sit in café corners and look at the eyes floating about, disjointed from their bodies&amp;ndash;out of sync. The cues are subtle at first, but soon the art is mastered. We capture souls as they walk past.
I am a connoisseur of beautiful souls, and a surgeon. I snatch up the rare specimens and breathe them deep inside, pulling the layers off piece by piece.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
